□ rafaelxm@gmail.com

+55 21 98636-4342

Rio de Janeiro, RJ - Brazil

ൂ്ന linkedin.com/in/rafael-xavier-miranda



rafaelxm.github.io



ABOUT ME

For more than 15 years, I've been working in the information technology area for companies from different market segments.

Always contributing and acquiring knowledge through interaction with the teams, I was able to experience the entire life cycle of projects of the most diverse kinds.

Throughout my career I was able to acquire solid knowledge in data and solution architecture areas, specifically of integrations, data warehouses and business intelligence.

Being result-oriented and attentive to the company's needs, I can cite as my greatest qualities: dedication, commitment, good communication, proactivity and teamwork.



WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Integrations Senior Analyst

Elera Renováveis - Rio de Janeiro - Brazil 2015 - Present

- I'm responsible for the company's entire integration ecosystem, configuring more than 130 integrations.
- I'm in charge of development, deployment, configuration, testing, support and management of 4 major integration platforms (iWay, Sql Server Integration Services, Digibee and Oracle Integration Cloud).
- . I'm also responsible for developing the company's data lake and it's ETL process, loading and integrating them with Azure Data Catalog. I also developed the commercial area data mart and created the integration's dashboard.
- I'm accountable for creating artifacts such as: functional and technical specifications, quick guides, architecture documents, solution drawings, management, governance documents, among others.

Data Consulting

MJV - Rio de Janeiro - Brazil 2012 - 2015

• I worked in insurance projects, being technically responsible for the corporate EDW, analyzing the loads and processes, as well as planning, organizing and executing the demands according to the client's methodologies.

Control and Information Analyst

Oi - Rio de Janeiro - Brazil 2011 - 2012

- I've worked in the development of BI projects, ensuring the structured growth of informational environment.
- Strengthening relation between the company areas, understanding their information needs and feasibilities, offering solutions proposals and enabling them in BI/DW systems.



SKILLS

Integrations Oracle / Sql Server **Business Intelligence** Data Warehouse / ETL **Data Modeling** Microsoft Power BI SOA **REST / SOAP** Agile Methodology DevOps Microsoft Azure Unix / Shell Scripting Python





LANGUAGES

English Spanish





EDUCATION

MBA in Business Intelligence UFRJ - Rio de Janeiro Nov 2015

Bachelor of Information Technology Unicarioca - Rio de Janeiro Nov 2008



CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Azure Data Fundamentals

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

Remote Work &Virtual Collaboration

DevOps Essentials Professional

Scrum Foundation Professional

Kanban Foundation

IBM SOA Associate

IBM Solution Designer